（忆往昔）
嘿 迪恩
Hey, Dean.
- 你回来多久了 - 一年了
- How long you been back? - About a year.
- 那你都在做些什么 - 猎魔抓鬼
- What have you been doing? - Hunting.
这一年来你一直都在这世上
You been back practically this whole time?!
你终于得偿所愿了 迪恩
You finally had what you wanted, Dean.
我要的是我弟弟 活着
I wanted my brother, alive.
你渴望的是家庭
You wanted a family.
只是由于我们的生存方式 你才不得不放弃
You only gave it up because of the way we lived.
但你已拥有了常人的生活 建立了家庭
But you had something, and you were building something.
我要你去 你就是个猎魔人
I need you to go. You're a hunter.
如今你弟弟出现了 事情就不一样了
And now you know your brother's out there. Things are different.
- 你不想呆这儿了 迪恩 - 不 我想
- You don't want to be here, Dean. - Yes, I do.
我和本仍会呆在这儿 而
Me and ben will be here, and…
只要可以你随时都能来
You come when you can.
但要答应我完好无损地回来
Just come in one piece.
你真觉得这样行得通吗
And you really think we could pull something like that off?
值得一试啊
It's worth a shot.
大天使们生性暴戾
Archangels are fierce.
而且专制跋扈
They're absolute.
他们是天堂最令人生畏的武器
They're heaven's most terrifying weapon.
拉斐尔
Raphael.
来抓我啊 你个小混球
Come and get me, you little bastard.
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
当圣油点燃时
When the oil burns,
任何天使都无法触碰或是跨越那些火焰
no angel can touch or pass through the flames,
否则他就会死
or he dies.
卡西迪奥
Castiel.
我要警告你
I'm warning you.
别把我留在这儿
Do not leave me here.
否则我定找你算账的
I will find you.
你现在打算怎么办
What are you gonna do now?
- 我想 得回天堂去 - 回天堂
- Return to heaven, I suppose. - Heaven?
鉴于米迦勒也关进了牢笼
With Michael in the cage,
我敢肯定如今的天堂定群龙无首 乱作一团
I'm sure it's total anarchy up there.
（如今）
噢 不是吧
Oh, come on.
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
快点 伙计 我们得出发了
Come on, man. Let's get going.
老杰
Jerry?
埃德 我想我正大出血
Ed, I think I'm bleeding.
[邪恶力量 第6季第3集]
早上好 帅哥
Hey, you.
早上好
Hey.
别因为我的出现就停下来啊
Don't stop on my account.
已经完事儿了
I'm done.
昨晚真是个
Last night was a…
高潮迭起之夜 希望你不介意我这样说
High point, if you don't mind me saying.
很好
Good.
好吧
All right.
看来对你而言新的一天已经开始了
Well, I see you need to start your day.
你说你什么时候出城来着
When did you say you were heading out?
你没说过 对吗
You didn't. Right.
该死的 你还真是会玩儿神秘
Damn, you know how to play that mystery card.
哦对
Right.
我差点儿都忘了
I almost forgot.
下次
Next time…
你可以在我下班的时候找我
You can call me on my night off.
如果你想的话
If you want.
好的
Okay.
- 喂 - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
我离坎贝尔大本营还有八小时了
I'm about eight hours out of the Campbell base.
计划有变
Uh, change of plans.
我要你来找我 我在宾州的伊斯特尔镇
I need you to meet me. I'm in P.A. … Town called Easter.
你在宾夕法尼亚干嘛
What are you doing in Pennsylvania?
跟一个案子
Caught a case.
一个案子
A case?
什么时候 这不才过了一天半么
When? It's been like a day and a half.
我喜欢找活儿干
I like to work.
显而易见
Apparently.
很高兴咱俩又开始纠结互喷了
Glad we hashed that out.
到镇时再打给我
Call me when you roll into town.
这丫跟谁装老大呢
Who died and made you boss?
你可以再快点儿
Oh, you could do better than that.
你找我啥事儿
Why are you calling me?
他已经死了 不是吗 就这样了
He's dead, right? That's it.
现在 我不想再讨论这事儿了
Now, I don't want to talk about it.
做好我们该做的
We do what we do …
我们按时上班 出席葬礼
We go to work, we go to the funeral.
冷静点
Calm down.
这件事和你我都无关
This is nothing to do with you and me.
你调整好自己情绪 别再打给我了
You're just working yourself up. Don't call me.
呆瓜
Idiot.
上帝啊
God!
调度中心 这是
Dispatch, this is …
劳驾 我 我需要
please, I … I need…
拜托
Please.
本 我知道你在撒谎
Ben…I know you're lying.
因为我可是这方面的专家 你骗不了我
Because I lie professionally, that's how.
现在告诉你妈 是你打破那该死的东西
Now tell your mom that you broke the damn thing.
像个男子汉一样负起责任来
and take it like a man.
听懂了吗 好的 乖
Okay? Ok… okay.
干嘛
What?
你 竟然在培育祖国未来花朵 真难想象
You … molding the minds of tomorrow. Who knew?
谁说不是呢
Yeah, tell me about it.
- 怎么样了 - 什么
- How'd it go? - With?
你和莉莎
You and Lisa.
对于你的离开她有什么反应
How'd she take it when you bailed?
事实上 她非常地冷静
Shockingly cool, actually.
这样对大家都好
Better for everybody.
是的 我想是的
Yeah, I suppose.
还在开这破玩意儿么
Still driving the plastic piece of crap, huh?
那你的算是废物再利用吗
What's your mileage, again?
闭嘴
Shut up.
林肯大街740号
警察局
停尸房
杰拉德·哈奇警官 17年的老手
Officer Gerald Hatch … 17-year veteran,
三天前被发现死在警察准备室
found dead in the ready room three days ago.
他还真是水分过多了啊
Somebody was over-hydrated.
基本上 是这样
basically, yeah.
这家伙差不多是 液化了
The guy just… Liquefied.
大部分的肌肉 骨头 致密的结缔组织
Most of the meat, bones, dense tissues …
全都转变成了血
They just turned to blood.
- 好吧 我真搞不懂 - 没人搞得懂
- Okay, I don't get it. - Nobody gets it.
不 你说的我懂了
No. I mean, I get that.
我是说 这个人都成一滩血水了
I'm saying, if the guy was a mop job,
我们还来停尸房做什么
then what are we doing in the morgue?
他还留下什么部件可以看吗
What's left of him to look at?
来这里不是看他
Not here to look at him.
这里
Here.
真恶心
Ooh. Bad news.
这是托比·格雷警官
Officer Toby Gray.
他刚刚被放进来
They just brought him in.
他被发现死在巡逻车里
Found him dead in his patrol car,
当时车停在城外的车速监视区
sitting at a speed trap on the outside of town.
「严重过敏反应」
"Extreme allergic reaction."
对 脓疮 从头到脚长满全身
Yeah. Boils. Covered from head to toe.
体内也有
Yeah, on the inside, too.
上面说他的气道里也塞满了
It says his airways are chock full of them.
你觉得是巫术搞的鬼么
This startin' to look a little witchy to you?
一开始我也这么想
That was my first instinct,
但是我没发现任何巫术的迹象
but I found zero signs of hexwork anywhere.
就我看来 肯定不是巫术什么的
Far as I can tell, witchcraft was not involved.
那个一滩血水男和这个脓疮男
There's got to be some sort of link.
肯定是有联系的
between, uh, skid mark and bubble wrap here.
毋庸置疑
No question.
- 有目击证人吗 - 有
- All right, well, can I get a witness? - Yep.
爱德·克尔法克斯警官
Officer Ed Colfax.
亲眼看见哈奇的身体瞬间崩塌成一滩血水
Saw Hatch go from a solid to a liquid.
又一个警察
Another cop?
哈奇的搭档
Hatch's partner.
你…
Were you, uh…
你在和我赛车吗
Were you racing me?
没啊
No.
只是想给你点颜色瞧瞧
I was kicking your ass.
真是成熟懂事啊
Very mature.
克尔法克斯警官在家吗
Hello? Officer Colfax?
神探哥 眼神很犀利嘛
Lookin' sharp, Kojak.
你们是谁
Who the hell are you?
爱德 我们是联邦调查局的
We're the fed, Ed.
你的搭档离奇死亡
We're here to ask you a few follow-up questions.
我们想就此问你几个问题
about your partner's death.
别费心了 这不关你们的事
Don't worry about it. It's nobody's business.
- 克尔法克斯警官 - 少多管闲事
- Officer Colfax - Don't worry about it!
老弟
Dude!
克尔法克斯警官
Officer Colfax?
伙计 你没事吧
Hey, man, you all right?
别多管闲事
Don't worry about it.
好的
Right.
听着 克尔法克斯警官 爱德
Look, officer Colfax … ed.
我们认为你的搭档是非正常死亡
We think that your partner died of unnatural causes.
你知道他有什么仇家吗
Did he have any enemies that you know of?
可以说有
you might say that.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
是谁
Who's that?
他们俩是咎由自取 我也是
They both had it coming. Me too.
下一个死的就是我
I'll be the next to go,
然后这事儿就完了
and then it'll be over.
上帝肯定心满意足了
And god will be satisfied.
上帝干嘛要你们全都去死
Why does god want you all dead?
因为克里斯多夫·伯奇
'cause of Christopher Birch.
该死的
Oh, damn it.
谁是克里斯多夫·伯奇
Who's Christopher Birch?
他没有脸
He has no face.
爱德
Ed?
警官你没事吧
Officer, you all right?
爱德 谁是克里斯多夫·伯奇
Who is Christopher Birch, Ed?
爱德
Ed!
克里斯多夫·伯奇是一个没有脸的小孩
Christopher Birch is a kid with no face…
还有栽赃的枪
…and a planted gun.
你
Uh, you, uh…
你这有点东西
You got a little something…
就那里
Yeah.
我靠
Damn.
我的头就像脏内裤一样痒死了
My head's been itching like a dirty jock.
爱德
Ed?
死了
Dead.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
酷啊 鲜血 脓疮 蝗虫
Sweet. Blood, boils, locusts.
埃及最盛行的三种瘟疫
Three of your more popular egyptian plagues.
但是这些小东西
Yeah, but these guys…
从警察的脑袋里钻出来
ate their way out of a cop's melon.
金·詹姆士版的圣经上可没这么写
I don't quite remember that in the King James.
与此同时 上个月一场警车追逐战中
Meanwhile, a kid named Christopher Birch.
一个叫克里斯多夫·伯奇的小孩
was shot in the head last month.
头部中枪而亡
after a vehicle pursuit.
哈奇 格雷和克尔法克斯都有参与此事
Hatch, Gray, and Colfax were the three officers involved,
他们三人的警方报告一模一样
and they all filed the exact same police report.
「嫌犯持枪走下了车
"Suspect exited vehicle brandishing a firearm.
我们被迫开枪「
We were forced to fire."
「只有一个没有脸的小孩
"Just a kid with no face.
和一把栽赃的枪「
and a planted gun."
一群混蛋
Bunch of dicks.
他们杀了这个孩子 还栽赃嫁祸
So they pop the kid, plant the piece.
克尔法克斯也许是对的
Maybe Colfax is right.
老天有眼 这些坏警察恶有恶报
You know, maybe heaven has a hate-on for bad cops.
我们要相信这个脑袋里有虫的警察吗
So we're listening to the guy with the bug in his custard?
这就是
That's … that's the, uh,
你真的相信这一套啊
The theory you want to go with?
迪恩 天使们该做点事儿了啊
Dean, angels got to have something to do, right,
我们现在是后天启时期
Now that we're post-apocalypse?
对 可能吧
Yeah, maybe.
我们召唤卡西吧
We should call Cass.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding, right?
迪恩 我试过了
Dean, I tried.
我一回到上面来
It was the first and second and third thing I did,
就整天召唤卡西
soon as I got topside.
那个龟儿子没反应啊
son of a bitch won't answer the phone.
我试试吧
Well, let's give it a shot.
现在我沉入梦乡
Now I lay me down to sleep.
愿卡西迪奥能扇着他毛茸茸的翅膀飞下来
I pray to Castiel to get his feathery ass down here.
- 你真白痴啊 - 乐观点嘛
- You're an idiot. - Stay positive.
我很乐观啊
Oh, I am positive.
卡西 快快显身
Come on, Cass!
别讨打哦
Don't be a dick.
我们
We got ourselves a…
遇到了一个瘟疫啥的状况
Plague-like situation down here.
你 你收到了吗
Do you…Do you copy?
如我所说
Like I said…
那个小混蛋不会理你的
The son of a bitch doesn't answer …
他现在就在我身后 是吗
He's right behind me, isn't he?
你好
Hello.
是的
Yes.
「你好」
"Hello."
"Hello"?
呃 这句话用来问好没错吧
Uh, that is still the term?
我那么长时间一直在努力联系你
I spent all that time trying to get through to you.
迪恩只呼唤了你这么一次
Dean calls once,
你就出来跟我们说「你好」
and now it's "Hello"?!
是啊
Yes.
所以你现在是更爱他还是怎样
So, what, you … you like him better or something?
迪恩和我确实有更深层次的羁绊
Dean and I do share a more profound bond.
我本来不想提的
I wasn't gonna mention it.
卡西 我觉得他想说的是
Cass, I think what he's trying to say is that…
他曾经为了我们去了地狱
He went to hell for us.
我是说 他为了大家牺牲了自己
I mean, he really took one for the team.
你还记得吗
You remember that?
然后他莫名其妙地回来了
And then he comes back without a clue,
而你却该死的连花五分钟时间
and you can't take five friggin' minutes.
给他个答案都不肯吗
to give him some answers?
如果我知道答案 我会回应的
If I had any answers, I might have responded.
但我真的不知道 萨姆
But I don't know, Sam.
我们也不知道究竟谁把你从那牢笼解放的
We have no idea who brought you back from the cage…
或者他为什么解放你
Or why.
所以 不是上帝吗
So…It wasn't god?
都没人看见过上帝
No one's even seen god.
这整件事都透着诡异
The whole thing remains mysterious.
这又是什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
「我也不知道」这句话里
What part of "I don't know"
哪个字你不懂
escapes your understanding?
卡西 听着 萨姆呼唤你就该回应
Cass, look, if Sam calls, you answer. Okay?
你扑闪着小翅膀飞过来
You wing your ass down here,
然后告诉他「我不知道」
and you tell him, "I don't know."
只是因为我俩之间有什么羁绊啥的…
Just because we have some sort of a … a bond or whatever…
你以为我来是因为你呼唤了我吗
You think I came because you called?
我过来是为了这个
I came because of this.
哦 我们可真想知道这到底怎么回事
Oh, well, it's nice to know what matters.
我大概能猜到是什么干的
It does help one to focus.
所以 你和那个天使巡逻队
Wait, so … so you and the halo patrol,
不是你们造成的这些杀戮吗
you guys aren't the cause of these killings?
不是
No.
但他们确实是被我们的某种武器杀死的
But they were committed with one of our weapons.
只有一个东西
There's only one thing.
能够造成这些死状
that could have brought this into existence.
你们叫它摩西之杖
You call it the staff of Moses.
那个权杖
The staff?
就我所知
It was used.
它曾经被用来反抗埃及统治者
in a dominance display against the egyptians, as I recall.
是啊 书里都写着呢
Yeah. That one made the papers.
但是那根权杖不是足以
B-but I thought the staff.
让世间血流成河吗
turned, like, a-a river into blood.
怎么就杀这么一个人
not one dude.
这还不是这种武器能造成的最大伤害
The weapon isn't being used at full capacity.
我想这不是摩西本人干的
I think we can rule Moses out as a suspect.
好吧 但是…
Okay, but…What is …
查克·赫斯顿的那根小棒棒怎么会在人间
你们难道不会把玩具收收好吗
I mean, don't you guys put away your toys?
在天启之前
Before the apocalypse,
天堂虽然已经堕落 但至少依旧稳固
heaven may have been corrupt, but it was stable.
权杖被安稳地保存着
The staff was safely contained.
在那次战争之后上面就混乱不堪
It's been chaos up there since the war ended.
混乱之中 很多很多
In that confusion, a number of…
杀伤性很强的武器
powerful weapons were…
被盗了
stolen.
等等 是说你们那些武器随时都可能发飙
Wait, you … you're saying your nukes are loose?
是的
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
但是你们遇上了其中一个
But you've stumbled onto one of them.
我们必须找到造成这一切的武器
We must find the weapon that did this.
我需要你们的帮助
I need your help.
太给力了 真的
That's rich. Really.
萨姆 迪恩
Sam, Dean,
我的「人类技能」已经「生疏」了
My "people skills" are "rusty."
真抱歉 不过我过去一整「年」
Pardon me, but I have spent the last "Year"
都在充当着帮助你们的
as a multi-dimensional wavelength.
天堂形象大使的角色
of celestial intent.
但是相信我
But believe me,
你们绝对不希望那武器来到世间
you do not want that weapon down here.
帮我找到它
Help me find it.
否则将有更多的人死去
Or more people will die.
- 好吧 - 好的
- All right. - Okay.
好吧 既然不是天使干的
Well, if the angels didn't pull the trigger,
那我们还是从动机查起吧
then that brings us back to motive.
什么
What?
回到案件本身
Back to the case.
现在 已经死了三个警察
Right now, we got three dead cops.
唯一能将他们联系到一起的是
Only thing linking them…
是这个
…is this.
「已故嫌疑犯的父亲要求彻查此案」
"Father of slain suspect calls for investigation."
[星星公报]已故嫌疑犯的父亲要求彻查此案
[东方鹰报]一名警察在执勤中死去
拜托 老爸
Come on, dad.
你到底要读多少遍那个东西
How many times are you gonna read that thing?
你知道吗 我们应该忘掉那件事情
You know what? We should just throw it away.
你出去玩吧
Go out back and play.
卡西 下次先提个醒好不
Oh, Cass, a little warning next time.
我靠
What the…
你们是怎么进来的
How'd you get in here?!
伯奇先生 别害怕
Mr. Birch, settle down.
我们是联邦探员
Federal agents.
可你们不能肆无忌惮地就闯进来吧
But you can't just walk in here!
你的收藏不少哇
Quite a collection you've got there, huh?
你想说什么…
What are you trying to …
听着 我们知道事情的真相
Look, we know the truth, all right?
在那些警察对克里斯开枪的时候
Chris didn't have a gun on him.
他并没有枪
when those cops shot him.
他们诬陷他
They set him up.
是的
Yeah.
他们总算得到报应了
They're all getting theirs.
那是谁在对他们进行报复呢 达里尔
And who's giving it to them, Darryl?
达里尔
Darryl?
是你杀了托比·格雷及其他人吗
Did you kill Toby Gray and the others?
我 我没有杀任何人
Me?! I didn't kill anyone!
你看看他们的死相
Look at how they died!
你用摩西之杖攻击了他们
You smote them with the staff of Moses!
你算哪门子的条子啊
The hell kind of fed are you?
我们没时间了
We don't have time for this.
那东西在哪儿
Where is it?
别动我爸
Leave my dad alone!
- 那难不成是… - 没错
- Is that…? - Yes.
- 不应该是个大家伙吗 - 没错
- Shouldn't it be bigger? - Yes.
那个… 是被锯掉了
It's … it's been sawed off.
- 放了他 不关他的事 - 艾伦 快离开这
- Leave him alone! It wasn't him! - Aaron, get out of here!
- 你把他怎么了 - 没事 他只是睡着了
- What did you do to him? - It's all right. He's just sleeping.
卡西 温柔点
Cass, take it easy!
听好 我们不是来伤害你们的
Listen, we're not here to hurt you, okay?
我们只需知道…
But we need to know…
你从哪里得到这东西的
where did you get this thing?
求求你们别杀我爸爸
Please don't kill my dad.
是我 是我干的
It was me. I did it.
好 没人要杀人
Okay, nobody's killing anybody.
你叫什么
What's your name?
艾伦·伯奇
Aaron. Aaron Birch.
好的艾伦·伯奇 你从哪得到的这个
Okay, Aaron Birch, where did you get this?
- 你肯定不信 - 说说看
- You won't believe me. - Try me.
是一个天使给我的
It was an angel.
天使
An angel?
那些骗子 他们杀了我哥哥
Those liars, they killed my brother,
却没有任何报应
and nothing bad even happened to them.
这不公平
It's not fair.
所以我每晚祈求上帝 给他们应有的惩罚
So I prayed to god every night he would punish them.
而上帝却从未回应
God didn't answer.
但他回应了
But he did.
他叫什么 有没有告诉过你
His name … did he give you a name?
没有
No.
他说我可以获得正义
He just said I could have justice,
但我要自己去争取
but I was gonna have to take it myself.
他… 他给了我这根木棒
He…He gave me the stick.
他就… 这么给你了
He just… Gave it to you?
得了吧
Ah, come on.
他不可能就这么白给你吧
He didn't just give it to you,
是吧 艾伦
did he, Aaron?
我买来的
I bought it.
买来的
You bought it?
用什么买
With what?
你有啥好给他的
What's your allowance?
那个天使想要什么
What did the angel want for it?
你给了他什么
What did you give him for it?
我的灵魂
My soul.
你把灵魂卖给了一个天使
You sold your soul to an angel?
这可能吗
Can that even happen?
之前从没发生过
It's never happened before.
天使会买灵魂
An angel's buying souls.
这倒是解释了他为什么要把这东西锯开
That could explain why he cut the staff into pieces.
为什么
Why?
武器越多 「产品」就越多
More pieces, more product.
啥叫「产品」 这人到底是谁
More "Product"? Who is this guy?
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
- 你这是干什么 - 方便
- What did you do that for? - Portability.
卡西 你知道你这是在拐个孩子吧
Cass, you realize you just kidnapped a kid?
若我们追踪的那个天使真买了他的灵魂
If the angel we seek truly bought this boy's soul,
当一个天使宣布了他对灵魂的所有权
when a claim is laid on a living soul,
就会留下记号 一个标志
it leaves a mark, a brand.
啥 就跟校服上的校徽似的么
What, like a … like a shirt tag at camp?
不知道你说啥
I have no idea.
但我能看懂那个记号
But I can read the mark.
找出买了这个灵魂的天使叫什么
and find the name of the angel that bought the soul.
怎么看
How?
这个 他要受苦了
Well, painfully for him.
这过程会极其痛苦
The reading will be excruciating.
喂喂喂 等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on.
- 迪恩 - 他只是个孩子 卡西
- Dean.- He's a kid, Cass.
孩子啊 萨姆你说
A ki… Sam?
会造成永久伤害吗
Any permanent damage?
- 说啥 - 身体上的伤害极其微小
- What?! - Physically, minimal.
得 那您就请随意吧
Oh, well, yeah, then by all means,
- 把胳膊插进去吧 - 迪恩
- stick your arm right in there. - Dean!
知道了名字 我就能用一个仪式查到他在哪
If I get the name, I can work a ritual to track the angel down.
我双手赞成 但是拜托
And I'm all for that. But come on.
- 肯定会有别的办法吧 - 没别的办法
- There's got to be another way. - There is no other way.
你要折磨一个孩子
You're gonna torture a kid?
我没闲心管那个了 迪恩
I can't care about that, Dean!
良知对我来说是奢侈品
I don't have the luxury.
他现在可以休息了
He'll rest now.
知道名字了吗 是什么
Did you get a name? What is it?
我还以为他在混战中死了
I thought he died in the war.
啥 他 他是敌是友
What, he … he was a … he was a friend or something?
一位挚友
A good friend.
是啊 你的好兄弟现在
Yeah, well, your frat buddy is now.
做起了买卖灵魂的兼职啊 跟恶魔有一拼
moonlighting as a crossroads demon.
我想应该是巴尔萨泽
Balthazar. I wonder…
就是说我们能找到他 对吗
So we can find him now, right?
巴尔萨泽
Balthazar.
谢了 卡西迪奥 这名字可真是管了大用了
Thanks, Castiel. We'll make good use of the name.
顺便说一句 拉斐尔向你问好
And by the way, Raphael says hello.
哥的车
My car.
不错 不幸中的万幸
Okay. Silver lining.
他跑了
He's gone.
卡西 那是谁
Cass, who was that guy?
拉斐尔的手下
A soldier of Raphael.
肯定在我来找你们的时候就跟上我了
He must have followed me when I answered your call.
拉斐尔 那大天使吗
Raphael? The archangel?
不好意思 这什么情况
I'm sorry, what's going on here?
我待会再解释 现在我们得…
I can explain later. Right now we have to …
别想待会 停下来 好吗
No, not later. Now. Stop, all right?
各种天使来捣乱 卡西
Too many angels, Cass!
我都不知道「谁」先来 「谁」还来
I don't know who's on first, what's on second.
是谁「又来」了
别跟我咬文嚼字
Don't start that.
很简单 拉斐尔和他的追随者们
It is simple … Raphael and his followers,
他们想让他去统治天堂
They want him to rule heaven.
我 还有很多别的天使们
I … and many others …
我们最不想看到的 就是他掌权
The last thing we want is to let him take over.
否则就是生灵涂炭
It would be catastrophic.
你是在说内战吗
You're talking civil war.
差不多 就是
Technically, yes.
所以我们必须在拉斐尔之前找到
Which is why we have to find Balthazar and his weapons.
巴尔萨泽和他的武器
Before Raphael does.
谁找到武器 谁就赢定了
Whoever has the weapons wins the war.
别客气 尽管用
Help yourself.
如果拉斐尔赢了会怎样
And what happens if Raphael wins?
- 他想要怎样 - 他一直想做的
- What … what does he want? - What he's always wanted …
像圣经里写的那样 结束这一切
to end the story the way it was written.
你是说我们阻止的那个天启吗
You mean the apocalypse, the one that we derailed?
没错 就是那个
Yes. That one.
拉斐尔想要再次开启天启
Raphael wants to put it back on the rails.
为什么
Why?
我需要没药
I need myrrh.
没药
Myrrh?
烦人的小翅膀
Friggin' angels.
拉斐尔为啥想再弄个天启出来
Why does Raphael want to bring back all this crap?
他是个传统主义者
He's a traditionalist.
卡西 你为何没告诉过我们这些
Cass, why didn't you tell us this?
我羞于启齿
I was ashamed.
我的兄弟们让我很失望
I expected more from my brothers.
对不起
I'm sorry.
现在 我需要你的血
Now I need your blood.
为什么不用你自己的
Whoa, whoa! Hey! Ahh! Why don't you use your own?
不管用 我不是人类
It wouldn't work. I'm not human.
[咒语]
Zamran ils soba vpaah zixlai grosb.
卡西
Uh, Cass,
这咒语需要多长时间
how long does this spell take?
找到他了 行动
Got him. Let's go.
他怎么办
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What about him?
警察会把他送回家的
Don't you think the police will take him home?
真没想到还挺有情调
卡西
Cass.
你来了
You're here.
巴尔萨泽
Balthazar.
真高兴见到你
It's so good to see you.
他告诉我你最近到处飞来飞去
He told me you were floating around.
他
He?
你俩不是一起的么
I believe you two float together.
你知道的 声音嘶哑什么的
Oh, you know, the old frog in the throat.
连我都知道这笑话太冷了
Even I know that that's a bad joke.
我还为你的死表示哀悼来着呢
I grieved your death.
哦对 关于那个真是不好意思
Yeah, yeah. I'm sorry about that, you know.
我想让他们以为我死了
I wanted them to think, you know,
那样 他们就不会来找我了
so… they wouldn't come looking for me.
这一切是怎么回事
What… is all this?
- 你在干什么 - 想干什么就干什么
- What are you doing? - Whatever I want.
今早我来了个多人行…
This morning I had a ménage à …
法语里12怎么说来着
What's French for 12?
你偷了摩西之杖
You stole the staff of Moses.
当然
Sure, sure.
我偷了很多东西
I stole a lot of things.
你曾是名值得尊敬的伟大战士
You were a great and honorable soldier.
我们一起战斗
We fought together.
是啊 已经数不清多少次了
Yes, too many times to count.
我了解你
I know you.
你不是一般的小偷
You're not some common thief.
一般吗 不
Common? No.
小偷吗 嗯
Thief? Eh.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我知道
I know.
你的那些事我都听说了
I've been hearing all about you,
卡西 对我来说 你和我…
and as far as I'm concerned, you and me, Cass…
一切如常
Nothing's changed.
我们还是兄弟 我当然想帮助你
We're brothers. Of course I want to help you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我需要那些武器
I need the weapons.
别要这个
Don't ask that.
为什么要拿走它们 为何要逃跑
Why take them? Why run away?
因为我做的到
Because I could!
怎么了
What?
怎么了 这一切都拜你所赐呢
What? I me… you're the one who made it possible.
我可是追随着你的脚步
The footsteps I'm following … they're yours.
你做的那一切 阻止天启
What you did, stopping the big plan,
背水一战
the prize fight?
你所做的远不止是背叛天堂
You did more than rebel.
你撕毁了整个蓝图
You tore up the whole script.
改变了我们所有人的命运
and burned the pages for all of us.
这是一个新时代
It's a new era.
没有什么规则和命运可言
No rules, no destiny.
只有完完全全的自由
Just utter and complete freedom.
所以你就这样享受这份自由吗
And this is what you do with it?
管它的呢
Hey, screw it, right?
我是说 爸爸不会回来了
I mean, dad's not coming back.
你也大可以随心所欲 花天酒地啊
You might as well blow coke and jump on the bed.
你向我证明了 一切皆有可能
You proved to me we could do anything,
所以我要体验一切可能
so I'm trying everything.
这有什么区别呢
What difference does it make?
当然有 天上正内战呢
Of course it makes a diff… it's Civil War up there!
我知道
I know.
若能打败拉斐尔
If we can beat raphael,
我们就能结束这一切
we can end this!
把武器给我
Just give me the weapons.
你知道你很可爱的一点是什么吗
Do you know what's funny about you?
你真以为自己能阻止这场战争
You actually believe that you can stop the fighting.
它永远不会停止
It will never stop.
我建议 带上些有价值的东西
My advice… grab something valuable.
然后佯装自己死了
and fake your own death.
你已经疯了
You've gone insane.
你悠哉的日子已经结束了
Your little holiday is over.
现在拉斐尔知道你还活着
Raphael knows you're alive by now.
拉斐尔可以随时来找我
Oh, Raphael can try me anytime.
我已全副武装
I'm armed.
对不起 卡西
I'm sorry, Cass.
抛开其他不谈 见到你我真的很开心
All else aside, I'm really, really happy to see you.
虽然你身后有个讨厌的跟屁虫
Even though you still have that stick up your ass.
是你干的吗
Was that you?
那就是给我的暗号了
Oh, that's my cue then.
让拉斐尔去使吧
Tell, uh, Raphael to bite me.
小心点 他们狡猾的很
Watch them. They're all snakes.
看这边
Hey, there.
我也有一把
Yeah, I got one of those, too.
你觉得自己可以用刀跟天使搏斗吗
You think you can knife fight an angel?
谁要打架了
Who's fighting?
快滚吧 一群孬货
Peace out, douchewad.
你这么做是错的
You're making a mistake.
拜托 还有别的解决办法
Please. There is another way.
兄弟 拜托 我不想伤害你
Brother, please. I don't want to hurt you.
你们为什么就是不听话呢
Why won't any of you listen?
他们当然不听 卡西迪奥
They don't listen, Castiel,
因为他们的心都是我的
because their hearts are mine.
不知何故 我觉得这次上帝不会救你了
Somehow, I don't think god will be bringing you back this time.
看我手上这玩意儿
Look at my junk.
不要
No.
罗德的妻子也是这么死的
碘化这个可怜虫
Iodize the poor sucker,
一辈子都不用愁没盐用了
and your kitchen is stocked for life.
你回来了
You came back.
现在拉斐尔得去买个新皮囊了
Well, now Raphael will have to go shopping for a new vessel.
这样到他下次换上皮囊前
Should give me a nice long head start on him.
我都有一段美好的时光
Until next time.
下一次
Next time.
机不可失 失不再来
No time like the present.
圣火
Holy fire.
你这个无毛的猿类 放了我
You hairless ape! Release me!
你先去除艾伦·伯奇灵魂上的标记
First you're taking your marker off of Aaron Birch's soul!
我为何这么做
Am I?!
萨姆
Sam?!
除非你想尝尝自己的劲脆天使翼
Unless you like your wings extra crispy,
我会考虑下
I'd think about it.
卡西迪奥 我在天堂帮过你
Castiel, I stood for you in heaven.
- 你要让 - 我相信
- Are you gonna let… - I believe…
这件事无毛猿类有发言权
The hairless ape has the floor.
很好
Very well.
那男孩欠我的一笔勾销了
The boy's debt is cleared.
他的灵魂归他自己所有
His soul is his own.
你到底为什么要买人类的灵魂
Why you buying up human souls, anyway?
在当下的经济状况下
In this economy,
这也许是唯一值得买的东西了
it's probably the only thing worth buying.
你知道灵魂有多大价值么
Do you have any idea what souls are worth?
拥有多大的力量
What power they hold?
现在 放了我
Now…release me.
去你的 混蛋 没人说过要放你
Suck it, ass clown. Nobody said anything.
卡西 你搞什么
Cass, what the hell?
我欠你的还清了
My debt to you is cleared.
很好
Fair enough.
卡西 你疯了吗
Cass, are you out of your mind?!
卡西
Cass?!
该死的天使们 回来啊
Oh, friggin' angels! Come on!
找到了
Yes.
我不知道我在这里放了这么多东西
I didn't realize I had this much stuff back here.
我需要一些放东西的空间
Well, I need some space.
这段时间搞到了很多东西
Kind of picked up some stuff along the way.
那是什么
What the hell is that?
这是本的万圣节面具
Oh, it's, uh, Ben's halloween costume.
雪怪温迪戈
Wendigo?
是
Yeah.
很像啊
Accurate.
那么
Hey, so, uh…
你还好吗
…are you okay?
我吗
Me?
好 我很好啊
Yeah, I'm great.
真的吗 因为有几次
Really? 'cause there's.
你让我觉得有点奇怪
been a few times that you got me wondering.
什么意思
Come again?
例如卡西「虐待」那个孩子的时候
Well, like where were you when Cass was, uh,
你去哪了
giving the holy taser treatment to that kid?
我就在那里啊
I was right there.
真的吗
Really?
因为老实说
'cause honestly,
我感觉只有我站出来反对卡西那么做
I felt like I was the only one raising a card.
好吧
Right.
我是说 我同意你的观点
Uh, I mean, I was with you,
但是…
but…I don't know.
我们需要通过他找到线索
W-we needed the intel.
我知道 但那线索是折磨那个孩子得来的
Yeah, I know, but we tortured that kid to get it.
我只是觉得你
I just didn't get the feeling that you…
你一点都不关心
that you even cared.
你错了
You're wrong.
兄弟 我想弄明白这件事是因为
Man, I'm just trying to figure this out because…
你变了
something's different with you.
你自己应该清楚
You know that.
是 我知道
Yeah. Yeah, I know.
真的吗
Really?
是
Yeah.
我是说
I mean…
过去几年我一直在不停地猎魔
I've been hunting nonstop for the past year,
类似…
Kind of…
四处奔波 你知道吗
Kind of out in the wild, you know?
所以 没错 我是有那么点不拘小节
So, yeah, I suppose I'm a little rough around the edges.
是 我明白
Yeah, I get that.
我只是觉得原因应该不止这么简单
I just don't think I'm getting the whole scoop.
萨姆 你去过地狱
You went to hell, Sam.
相信我 我知道那会对人造成怎样的伤害
And believe me, I know what that does to a guy.
对你
To you.
什么
What?
你知道那会对你造成怎样的伤害
You know what it does to you.
它折磨过你
It … it tortured you.
你知道
You know?
我觉得它现在还在影响你
I think it still does.
但 迪恩
But, Dean…
我没事
I'm okay.
所以你是说
So you're saying, what,
你比我坚强
That … that you're stronger than me?
不是
No.
只是说我们有所不同
Just saying we're different.
最近的妖怪们
Monsters lately.
是我的幻觉还是事有蹊跷
Is it me or is it weird?
小心
Look out!
吸血鬼吗
Vampires?
这些不是吸血鬼 兄弟
These aren't vampires, man.
这些是
These…
这些是一群傻逼
These are douche bags.
和我解释一下到底发生了什么
Explain to me what's going on out there.
莉莎 我不能把这些烂七八糟的事情带给你
Lis, I can't bring this crap home to you.
你是说你的工作吗
You're talking about your work.
我是说我的人生
I'm talking about my life.
城里的任何人大肆询问真相时
Anyone in town who asks aloud for the truth.
都会引来真理女神
Invokes Veritas.
她不是简简单单地给你真相
And she doesn't just give it to you.
而是用真相猛击你
She slams you with it.
凭什么我要告诉你这个
Whoa, why the hell am I telling you this?
因为我受了诅咒
Because I'm cursed.
我是说我寻问了真相 猜猜怎么了
I'm saying I asked for the truth, and, uh, guess what?
我知道了
I'm getting it.
所以就像我之前所说 对你我满肚子疑惑
So, like I said, I have a few questions for you.
迪恩 你还好吗
Dean, you all right?
鲍比 是萨姆的问题
It's Sam, Bobby.
有你帮我
You got my back.
不管发生什么 我都可以信赖你
No matter what happens, I can always count on you,
对吗 小萨姆
Right, Sammy?
当然了 迪恩
Yeah.Of course, Dean.